The path in the clouds looks just like an obi.
كأنما الغيوم حَبَكت طريقًا حِزاميًّا
It doesn't appear to have formed naturally.
لا يبدو أنها تكوَّنت طبيعيًّا
Oh, Nami!
يا لجمالك يا نامي-سان
There's no way this is natural!
محال أن يكون تكوّنها طبيعيًّا
There's the exit! Something's written on it!
!إنّه المخرج، هناك شيء مكتوب
God Land...
...أرض الإله
God Land, Skypiea?!
أرض الإله، سكايبيا؟
It's not an exit...
...ليس مخرجًا
it's an entrance!
!بل مدخل
An island!
!جزيرة
It's the sky island!
!إنّها جزيرة السماء
Hey... that sign... said Skypiea.
«كان مكتوب على تلك اللافتة «سكايبيا
Yeah!
أجل
The map Luffy found had that same name written on it.
إنّه نفس الاسم المكتوب على الخريطة التي وجدها لوفي
So the galleon that fell on us really did come from here.
سفينة الغليون التي سقطت علينا قد جاءت من هنا حقًّا
They witnessed this view 200 long years ago!
رأوا هذا المنظر قبل مئتي سنة
What is this place?!
ما هذا المكان؟
You can totally smell adventure in the air!
أشتمّ رائحة مغامرة
Ah! Wait, you idiot!
أيّها الغبي، تمهّل
You can stand up in it.
يمكننا الطفو عليه
Hey! You okay, Usopp?
هل أنت بخير يا أوسوب؟
So this island's made of fluffy clouds?
أهذه الجزيرة مصنوعة من الغيوم المنفوشة؟
They're super fluffy, right?
إنّها منفوشة، أليست كذلك؟
So fluffy!
!إنّها منفوشة
Let's go to the shore!
لنذهب إلى الشاطئ
The sky island!
!جزيرة السماء
Me too! Me too!
!أنا أيضًا، أنا أيضًا
I'm gonna go change!
سأذهب لتغيير ملابسي
Hey, Luffy! What about the anchor?
يا لوفي، ماذا نفعل بشأن المرساة؟
There's no sea floor out here, right?
لا قعر لهذا البحر
Who cares?
لا يهمّ ذلك
Yeah, who cares?!
لا يهمّ فعلًا
Yeah!
!أجل
Just forget about it!
!انسَ الأمر
Me too! Me too!
!أنا أيضًا، أنا أيضًا
Come down already! This beach is super fluffy!
انزلوا بسرعة، هذا الشاطئ منفوش
Let me do it too!
دعني أفعلها أيضًا
This view is amazing.
على أيّ حال، إن هذا لمنظرٌ مهيبٌ حقًا
It's like something out of a dream.
وكأنّه حلم
Yeah, it sure is.
فعلًا
And look at how they're getting all carried away.
...وها هم قد اندفعوا بكل حماسة
They're hopeless...
...ما باليدّ حيلة
Yahoo!
!مرحى
As if you aren't.
...اندفعت مثلهم
Ow! Ow! Ow! Sorry! I said sorry!
!مؤلم، مؤلم، مؤلم، آسفة، قلت آسفة
I guess we brought the south bird with us, huh?
...نسيت أنّنا أخذنا طير الجنوب معنا
We forgot to let him go.
نسينا أن نطلق سراحه
It looks like people are living here, so he'll likely get by without our help.
يبدو أنّ هنالك أُناسٌ يعيشون هنا، لذا سينجو إن تركناه على الأرجح
If he really tries, he could even get back down.
بمقدور الطائر الهبوط إلى الأرض بجهده، فهذه طبيعته
Oh, hey, what about the anchor?
صحيح، ماذا عن المرساة؟
It hit bottom.
،ضربت القاع
Looks like those fluffy clouds are the base of this island.
يبدو أنّ تلك الغيوم المنفوشة هي أساس هذه الجزيرة
That means that the island is floating on this sea.
ذلك يعني أنّ هذه الجزيرة تطفو فوق الماء
I wonder if an island can remain in the same spot without drifting away.
أتساءل عن مقدرة الجزيرة على الثبات في مكانها دون انجراف
Well, all we can do is take things as they come.
مهما يكن الأمر، كل ما في وسعنا هو القبول بالواقع كما هو عليه
Actually, all of this is hard to believe.
في الحقيقة، يصعب تصديق كلّ هذا
The only thing we know for sure is that this sky island exists.
وعلى أيّ حال، وجود جزيرة السماء حقيقة لا غبار عليها
See?!
أترين؟
There's no denying what's right in front of me.
شعرت بها بجسدي، لذا ليس هناك داعٍ للشك
Get down here!
انزلي أنتِ أيضًا
You can't drown when it's this shallow, right?!
طالما تلمس قدماكِ القاع، فلا خوف من الغرق
What about you?
ماذا عنك؟
Yeah, I'll go too.
سأنزل أيضًا
The smell of adventure, huh?
رائحة مغامرة إذًا؟
I've never thought of sailing or going ashore...
...ما خطر ببالي قط أن الإبحار أو النزول إلى الشاطئ
as an adventure.
قد يُعدّ مغامرة...
For some reason, this sky island is making me sleepy...
...لسبب ما، تجعلني جزيرة السماء أشعر بالنعاس
Hello, this is your captain speaking.
مرحبًا، قبطانكم يتحدث
I'm having too much fun to figure out what we should do first, over.
إنني منغمسٌ بالمتعة ولا أدري بما أبدأ، حوّل
This is Usopp. Why don't we take it easy for a bit, over.
أوسوب يتحدث، لمَ لا نسترخِ هنا لبعض الوقت؟ حوّل
Take it easy? Sounds good!
نسترخي؟ ذلك رائع
Denied!
!مرفوض
What?! "Denied" means no, you know!
مرفوض؟ ذلك يعني أنّك لا تريد، لعلمك
Look here...
عجبًا، هذه الورود الغريبة تُزهر
I wonder if they're also balloons.
أتساءل إن كانت بالونات أيضًا
Do they pop like that fish did?
أتتفرقع مثل تلك السمكة؟
This is so nice.
يا له من شعور لطيف
The Marines won't be chasing us here, so we can relax and enjoy ourselves!
لن تلاحقنا البحريّة هنا لذا بوسعنا الاستمتاع على مهلنا
Hey, Chopper, look. What could that be?
انظر يا تشوبر، ما ذلك يا ترى؟
Ah! I found a strange fruit!
وجدت فاكهة غريبة
I'm gonna try it!
شكرًا على الطعام
What the...?
ما هذه؟
This thing's hard!
!إنّها صلبة
Hey, Usopp! I've got a fruit for you. Here!
!يا أوسوب، سأعطيك فاكهة، خذ
Hey, that hurt! Okay, stay right there!
!هذا مؤلم أيّها الوغد، حسنًا، امهلني
Ahh! Robin my love!
!روبين-تشوان
These are sky island flowers. One for Robin my love...
...هذه ورود جزيرة السماء، واحدة لك يا روبين-تشوان
and one for...
...والأخرى
Nami my sweet!
!نامي-سوان
Nami my sweet! A flower for you!
!نامي-سوان! وردةُ لك
Whoa! This chair is made of clouds, too!
مذهل، هذا الكرسي مصنوع من الغيوم أيضًا
There must be some technology to make items from clouds.
لا بد أن هناك تقنية لصنع الأشياء من الغيوم
But it's different from the fluffy clouds.
،ولكنّها مختلفة عن الغيوم المنفوشة
It's puffy.
فهذه منتفخة
Nami! A flower for you!
نامي-سان، جلبت لك وردة
But why am I getting wet if this is just a sea of clouds?
لماذا أتبلّل في بحرٍ من الغيوم؟
Sorry!
المعذرة
Huh? What the hell is this? A fox?
ما هذا؟ ثعلب؟
Hmm? What's that sound?
ما هذا الصوت؟
Hey. Who is that person? Up there!
!مهلًا، ثمّة أحدٌ هناك
Did that guerrilla return?!
ذلك الفدائيّ ثانيةً؟
Whistle! Where's the whistle?! Let's ask that guy to save us again!
!الصافرة، أين الصافرة؟ لنطلب منه أن يأتي لنجدتنا مجدّدًا
No, hold on. That's not a guerrilla. That's...
...لا، تمهلّوا. ليس هو، بل هذه
an angel...
...ملاك
An angel?
ملاك؟
Heso!
هيسو
– Heso! – Heso?
هيسو؟
Suu, come here.
سو، تعالي هنا
Did you come from the Blue Sea?
هل حضرتكم من البحر الأزرق؟
Yeah, we flew up here from below.
أجل، طرنا إلى هنا من الأسفل
Do you live here?
أتعيشين هنا؟
Yes, I'm a resident here.
نعم، أنا من السكان
Welcome to Skypiea's Angel Beach!
أهلًا بكم في شاطئ الملائكة في سكايبيا
Would you like to drink that?
أتريد شرب هذه؟
Hm? Yeah...
...ماذا؟ أجل
A conash's shell is as hard as iron, so you can't bite it.
قشرة كوناش صلبة كالحديد، لذا لا ينبغي عضّها
You cut it at the bottom.
بل قطعها من الأسفل
Here you go!
تفضّل
Yum!
!لذيذة
What?! It's that good?!
ماذا؟ ألهذه الدرجة؟
Let me try it, too!
!دعني أجربها
Yum!
!لذيذة
My name is Conis.
اسمي كونيس
This is Suu, a cloud fox.
وهذه سو ثعلبة الغيم
If I can be of any help at all, please let me know.
إن كان ثمة ما يمكنني أن أُعينكم به، فأنا رهن إشارتكم
Well, you see...
...في الحقيقة
your gaze is setting my heart ablaze–
...نظرتك توقد نيران قلبي
Ow!
!مؤلم
Move it!
!ابتعد
There's so much we'd like to know.
هناك العديد من الأمور التي نود معرفتها
To us, this place is full of mysteries.
هذا المكان حافلٌ بالأسرار بالنسبة لنا
Okay. Please ask me anything.
نعم، تفضلي واسأليني أيّ شيء
Hey, something's coming.
مهلًا، ثمّة شيء قادم
Oh, that's my father.
هذا أبي
Heso, Conis!
كونيس-سان، هيسو
Yes, heso, Father!
أجل، هيسو يا أبي
Hey, what are you guys saying?
ماذا تقولان؟
Hm? What's that thing he's riding on?
ما ذلك الذي يركبه؟
Oh, are you talking about the waver?
أتتحدثين عن الويفر؟
Wow! That thing is so cool!
!هذا رائع
Waver...
...ويفر
I'm sorry, I'm coming to a stop!
المعذرة، سأتوقف
Is everyone all right?
هل أنتم بخير جميعًا؟
You're the one who crashed!
!أنت من اصطدم
Hey, Luffy. Didn't you salvage something similar from the seabed before?
يا لوفي، ألم تحضر شيئًا مشابهًا لهذا من أعماق البحر من قبل؟
Yeah, I did, didn't I?
بلى
I read about it in Noland's diary—
...هذا هو القارب الذي قرأت عنه في مذكرة نولاند
a boat that can be propelled without wind!
القارب الذي يندفع بلا رياح
Are they your friends, Conis?
أهؤلاء أصدقاؤك يا كونيس-سان؟
Yes. We've just become acquainted.
أجل. تعرفتُ عليهم توًّا
They're from the Blue Sea.
يبدو أنّهم أتوا من البحر الأزرق
I see. Then there must be many things that you're wondering about.
فهمت، لا بد أن هناك أمورًا كثيرة تُراودكم إذًا
This is the White-White Sea. I'm sorry.
هذا المكان هو البحر الأبيض-الأبيض، المعذرة
Oh, no need to apologize.
...لا، لا داعي للاعتذار
Pardon my late introduction, but my name is Pagaya. I'm sorry.
أعتذرُ عن تأخري في التعريفِ بنفسي، اسمي باغايا. المعذرة
Oh, no, no, no. We're sorry.
لا، لا، لا عليك... سررنا بمعرفتك
Father, were you able to catch some fish?
يا أبي، هل استطعت صيد السمك؟
Yes, I had a large haul.
أجل، الكثير
Oh, yes, why don't you all come to our house?
صحيح، ما رأيكم أن تشرفونا في منزلنا؟
I'll make a meal for you with the sky food.
سأعدّ لكم الطعام باستخدام محاصيل السماء
Are you sure?! Then let's go! Let's go!
!أيمكننا ذلك؟ لنذهب، لنذهب
Sky island cuisine?!
طعام جزيرة السماء؟
Let me help you!
!اسمح لي بمساعدتك
Before we go, can I ask you a question?
قبل ذلك، هل يمكنني أن أطرح سؤالًا؟
This boat doesn't have a sail, and you weren't paddling, either.
لا يملك هذا القارب شراعًا، ولم تكن تجدّف أيضًا
How did you propel it on the sea?
كيف كنت تسيّره عبر البحر؟
Oh, so you're not familiar with dials?
عجبًا، ألا تعرفون الدايل؟
Hm? Dials?
دايل؟
Wh-What is this shaking?! I can't stop it!
!مـ-مـ-ما هذا الاهتزاز؟ لا أستطيع إيقافه
Oh, no! Is he all right?!
هذا سيّئ، أهو بخير؟
Heavens! I let him use the waver. I'm sorry!
يا للمصيبة، أعتذر عن السماح له باستخدام الويفر
On that note, I wonder how this sea treats those with powers.
يا ترى، كيف وضع المتمتعين بالقدرات في هذا البحر؟
Oh, yeah. This isn't an ordinary sea,
صحيح، إنّه مختلف عن البحر العادي
so he may just float.
قد يطفو فحسب
He sank.
لقد غرق
So he doesn't float.
لم يستطع إذًا
Ahh! He's in danger!
!هذه مصيبة
That was close! He was just about to go through the clouds!
كان ذلك وشيكًا، كاد أن يعبر خلال الغيوم
We had a late start because of your nonsense!
تأخرنا بسبب تفوهك بأمور غبيّة
Did you really have to jump in too?
يا إلهي، لماذا قفزت أنت أيضًا؟
Sky island scary, sky island scary...
...جزيرة السماء مرعبة، جزيرة السماء مرعبة
I let a beginner use my watercraft. I'm sorry.
أعتذر عن السماح لهاوٍ باستخدامه
Wavers are so light that their rudders are easily taken over even by small waves.
هيكل الويفر خفيف جدًّا لدرجة أن بإمكان الأمواج الصغيرة أن تتحكم بدفته
Unless you know the sea well, you'll have difficulty handling it. I'm sorry.
يصعب التحكم بها ما لم تكن ملمًّا جيّدًا بالبحر. المعذرة
I've only recently learned how to ride it.
قد أصبحت قادرة على قيادتها مؤخرًا أخيرًا
It's that hard?
أذلك صعب إلى تلك الدرجة؟
Well, with training, you can ride it in about ten years.
عشر سنوات من التدريب كفيلة بأن تجعلك قادرًا على قيادته
That's a lot of training!
!لا بد أن تعلمه لمشقّة
Hey, she's riding it!
!إنّها تقوده
This is awesome!
!هذا رائع
Nami! You're the coolest!
!نامي-سان، أنتِ الأروع
Whoa! This is incredible! I can't believe it!
عجبًا، هذا مذهل، لا أصدّق ذلك
How is she able to ride that thing?!
كيف تستطيع قيادة ذلك الشيء؟
It definitely requires some getting used to!
إنّها تتطلب التأقلم على قيادتها فعلًا
This is too delicate for you to handle, Luffy!
إنّها حسّاسة جدًّا لتستطيع التحكم بها يا لوفي
Hey, Nami!
يا نامي، سنذهب إلى منزل العمّ لذا انزلي على الفور
You stupid head!
أيّتها الغبيّة
Give it up!
لا تفرّغ غضبك عليها
You guys go on ahead!
اسبقوني
Mister! Can I stay out here a little longer and have fun?
يا عم، هل يمكنني اللهو أكثر قليلًا؟
That's fine! Be careful!
أجل، توخي الحذر
It's like a dream! I'm sailing a boat so easily without a care for the wind's direction!
!أن أجوب بقارب دون اعتبارٍ لهبوب الريح أشبه بحلمٍ
I wonder if we can use it on the regular sea.
هل يمكن استخدامه في البحر العادي يا تُرى؟
Hey! Is that a construction site?
أذلك موقع بناء؟
Oh, that's a cloud quarry.
إنّه موقع تنقيب الغيم
It's a site where they mine clouds for other applications.
إنّه موقع ينقّبون منه الغيوم لتصنيعها
You can mine clouds?
أيمكن قطع الغيوم؟
You took a milky road to get to the White-White Sea, right?
سلكتم نهر الغيم للوصول إلى البحر الأبيض-الأبيض، أليس كذلك؟
Milky road? Oh, you mean that winding sea path?
نهر الغيم؟ أتعني ذلك الطريق البحري المتعرّج؟
That's an artificial canal.
إنها قناة اصطناعيّة مصنوعة من غيوم الجزيرة التي يُنقّب عنها هنا
There are two kinds of natural clouds.
،هناك نوعان طبيعيّان من الغيوم
The ones your ship traveled on are called sea clouds,
التي سارت سفينتكم عليها تُدعى غيوم البحر
and the floating ones that you can walk on are called island clouds.
والعائمة هناك التي تستطيعون المشي عليها تُدعى غيوم الجزيرة
Either way, they're not ordinary clouds.
إنّها ليست غيوم عاديّة على أيّ حال
Right. Their condensation nucleus is different from other clouds.
صحيح، نوى تكاثفها مختلف عن الغيوم الأخرى
I've heard that a mineral called seastone exists in the Blue Sea.
سمعت أنّ هناك معدن يدعى بالحجر البحري في البحر الأزرق
Seastone? Is there a connection to these clouds?
الحجر البحري؟ أله علاقة بهذه الغيوم؟
Yes.
أجل
When the stone's corneous particles, known as pyrobroin,
،حين تُنقَل الجسيمات القَرنيّة المعروفة بالبايروبلوين
are carried into the sky by volcanoes, they gain moisture.
من الحجر إلى السماء بفعل البراكين، وتكتسب الرطوبة حينها
Then, sea and island clouds form depending on the moisture's density.
ثم تتكون غيوم البحر والجزيرة بحسب كثافة الرطوبة
Oh, I see. That particle.
...فهمت... تلك
Oh, yeah, that one.
...نعم... صحيح، تلك
We used to play with them a lot as kids... corneous particles...
...اعتدنا اللعب بها كثيرًا في طفولتنا... الجسيمات القرنيّة
Cut the crap!
!كف عن الهراء
Well, anyway, there are three cloud types here.
على أيّ حال، هناك ثلاثة أنواع من الغيوم هنا
Sea and island clouds, which are natural,
وهم غيوم البحر والجزيرة، وهي غيوم طبيعية
and man-made ones that are processed from island clouds.
والغيوم الاصطناعية المصنوعة من غيوم الجزيرة
Now, this way, please.
والآن، تفضلوا من هنا
What a great view!
!يا له من منظر رائع
Oh! We can see Nami riding the waver, too!
بإمكاننا رؤية نامي على متن الويفر من هنا
Hey, Luffy, what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل يا لوفي؟
Why can she ride it so easily?
كيف بوسع نامي قيادته بسهولة؟
Sink!
!فلتَغرقي
Grow up!
!انضج
Ouch! You made me bite my tonuge, Sanji!
مؤلم، عضضتُ لساني توًّا يا سانجي
Hey, mister! Where's the kitchen?
أيّها العم، أين المطبخ؟
Come! It's right this way!
أجل، من هنا
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Well, I've never seen this before, so I had a little taste,
بدا غريبًا لي، لذا جربت تذوقه
but, how should I say it, this blue sauce's flavor was intense.
لا أدري كيف أصفها، لكن نكهة هذه الصلصة الزرقاء كانت شديدة
It made my tongue numb.
خدّرت لساني
That one's spoiled. I'm sorry.
المعذرة، إنّها متعفنة
Hey, don't keep stuff like this around!
!لا تبقي أشياء كهذه هنا
I tried it without thinking it'd be spoiled!
!تذوّقتها دون أن يخطر ببالي أنها فاسدة
It sounds like they're having fun.
يبدوان مبتهجان هناك
You knew it was going bad, right?!
!كنت تعلم أنها فاسدة، أليس كذلك؟
He's probably excited about all the new sky food.
لا عجب في حماسه، فطعام السماء جديد عليه
Miss, I don't mean to be abrupt, but...
...أعلم أنّ هذا مفاجئ أيّتها الآنسة
would you tell us more about the dials you mentioned earlier?
هل يمكن أن تخبرينا أكثر عن الدايل التي أشرتِ إليه سابقًا؟
Sure. Well... how should I explain it?
أجل! ولكن كيف أفسرها يا ترى؟
Ah... This is a puffy chair.
يا له من كرسي منتفخ رائع
Hm? What? It's a seashell.
ما هذه؟ إنّها قوقعة
Yes. Please say something to it.
نعم. تفضّل وقل لها شيئًا من فضلك
Usopp is stupid!
!أوسوب مغفل
Hey! Why?
لماذا؟
Why? Why me?
لماذا؟ لماذا أنا؟
Now, please press the apex of that shell.
والآن اضغط على طرف القوقعة
What's an apex?
ما هو الطرف؟
It's the tip of the shell.
تعني أعلى القوقعة
Usopp is stupid!
أوسوب غبي
Hey! Why? Why? Why me?
لماذا؟ لماذا؟ لماذا أنا؟
Ahh! The seashell made fun of Usopp!
سخرت القوقعة من أوسوب
No, that's your voice!
لا، هذا صوتك
Now, please press the apex of that shell.
والآن اضغط على طرف القوقعة
Whoa! That's amazing! It stored the sounds?
مذهل، أتخزّن الأصوات؟
So that seashell is a dial?
هذه القوقعة دايل إذًا؟
Yes. This is called a tone dial.
نعم. تُسمّى هذه قوقعة الصوت
It's a seashell from the White-White Sea that records and replays sounds.
هذه قوقعة من البحر الأبيض-الأبيض، تسجّل الأصوات وتعيد تشغيلها
But the sea here is bottomless, right?
ولكن لا قعر لهذا البحر، أليس كذلك؟
Where do they live?
أين تعيش؟
They live in the reefs of the shallows.
إنّها تعيش في الشعاب المرجانيّة من المياه الضحلة
But an object like that shouldn't be able to move a waver.
لا يُفترض أن يحرّك شيء كهذا الويفر
You're right. This is the kind that powers the wavers.
صحيح. هذه التي تحرّك الويفر
This is a small one,
،هذه صغيرة
but it's fundamentally the same as the tone dials.
ولكنّ أساسها يشبه دايل الصوت
So, wind comes out of this one.
إذًا فهذه تصدر الرياح
Let me try it.
دعيني أجربها
This is called a breath dial.
تدعى هذه دايل النّفس
You can store wind and release it at any time.
إنّها تسمح لك بتخزين الرياح وإطلاقها متى أردت
The capacity varies depending on the size of the shell,
،تختلف سعتها حسب حجم القوقعة
but by attaching this to the stern, you can move a light boat.
ولكن بوضعها في مؤخرة قارب خفيف، فستتمكن من تحريكه
That's the waver.
هذه آلية الويفر إذًا
I see. So, it moved by blowing wind.
فهمت... إنّه يتحرك عن طريق نفخ الهواء
I wanna ride a waver.
الويفر رائع حقًا
There are actually other kinds, like a skating type or board type,
،هناك عدّة أنواع في الحقيقة، كنوع التزلّج ونوع اللوح
although riding the waver is as much as I can handle.
ولكن ركوب ويفر هو أقصى ما يمكنني فعله
I wanna ride it.
أريد ركوبه
I'm jealous of Nami.
يا لحسن حظّها
Too bad we can't use the one we have.
من المؤسف أنّنا نملك واحدًا ولا نستطيع ركوبه
You have a waver?
ألديكم ويفر؟
Yeah, we came across one that was all beat up.
أجل، صادف أنّنا وجدنا واحدًا في حالة سيّئة
But for starters, it's 200 years old. There's no way it works.
عمره مئتان سنة من الأساس، لذا يستحيل أن يتحرّك
We can't know that for sure.
لا يمكن الجزم بذلك
Dials were always made with the remains of dead shellfish,
،لطالما صُنعت الدايل باستخدام بقايا القواقع الميتة
so they'll work practically forever unless the shell itself is damaged.
مما جعلها تعمل إلى الأبد تقريبًا، ما لم تتضرر القوقعة ذاتها
See?!
أترى؟
But you can't steer it, right?
ولكنّك لا تستطيع ركوبه، أليس كذلك؟
I'm jealous...
...يا لحسن حظّها
Sounds like other kinds of dials exist as well, huh?
يبدو أنّ هناك أنواع أخرى، أليس كذلك؟
Is this one, too?
أهذه كذلك أيضًا؟
Yes. It's a lamp dial.
أجل، إنّها دايل المصباح
Whoa! The seashell lit up!
!أضاءت القوقعة
Dials are varied. For instance, flame dials hold fire;
علاوة على ذلك، هناك دايل اللّهب، التي تخزن النيران
flavor dials, scents;
،ودايل المذاق التي تخزّن الرائحة
and vision dials, moving pictures.
ودايل الرؤية التي تخزّن الفيديوهات، وغيرهم الكثير
How interesting! How interesting!
!هذا شيّق، شيّق
To people in the sky, they're indispensable.
لا يمكن لقاطني السماء الاستغناء عنها
I see.
فهمت
So, you could say that...
...لذا، يمكن القول أنّ
sky culture goes hand in hand with dial energy.
حضارة السماء قائمة على طاقة الدايل
Now, the food is ready!
وها قد جهز الطعام
It's a hearty sky seafood course with sky island fruits!
إنها وجبة مأكولات بحريّة سماوية شهيّة مع فواكه جزيرة السماء
Wow!
!عجيب
Amazing!
!مذهل
Yum!
!لذيذة
This lobster...! How can I put its taste into words?!
هذا السلطعون، كيف يمكنني التعبير عن لذّته؟
Hey, where did Nami go?
أين ذهبت نامي-سان؟
She's out there on the sea, isn't she?
أليست تجوب البحر؟
No, she isn't.
كلا، لا أراها
Then she probably went farther out. Don't worry about her.
ربّما ابتعدت، لا تقلق بشأنها
Father, I wonder if she's all right.
أبي، هل هي بخير يا ترى؟
So do I, Conis. It's a bit concerning.
أجل يا كونيس-سان، أنا قلق قليلًا كذلك
Why? What's the matter?
لماذا؟ ما الخطب؟
Here in Skypiea,
في سكايبيا، يوجد مكان يُحرّم دخوله مهما حدث
That place is next to this island.
ذلك المكان بجوار هذه الجزيرة
So if you travel a bit by waver, you can get there.
...لذا يمكنك الوصول إليه إن استقليت ويفر
It's huge...
...يا لضخامتها
What is this?
ما هذه؟
Forbidden from entering?
يُحرّم دخولها؟
Why's that?
لماذا؟
It's sacred ground.
إنّها أرض مقدّسة
Sacred ground?
أرض مقدّسة؟
We call that place...
...يُطلق على ذلك المكان
Upper Yard, the land in which our god lives.
الساحة العليا، حيث يعيش الإله
God Land, Skypiea White-White Sea
«أرض الإله «سكايبيا البحر الأبيض-الأبيض
Conis & Cloud Fox Suu Angel Beach, Skypiea Residents
«كونيس» وثعلبة الغيم «سو» من سكان شاطئ الملائكة في سكايبيا